<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<book author="Shoghi_Effendi" language="en" pages="276" religion="bahai" source="Bahá’í Canada Publications" title="Messages to Canada">
    <section title="Foreword">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Preface">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Foreword to the 1965 edition">
        <p>and are now a part of the heritage of the entire Bahá’í world. The Canadian National Spiritual Assembly has long desired to contribute to that inheritance this final share of the trust left to it by the Guardian. No more fitting occasion could be found than the inauguration of the first of the global plans designed by the Universal House of Justice and inspired by just such undertakings as form the subject of much of this book.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Introduction to the 1965 edition By Hand of the Cause, John A. Robarts">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="&quot;O my loving friends! After...&quot;">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="The Guardian’s First Letter to Canada">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="The Early Years 1923–1937">
        <p>has received from America, all gave me the assurance that a new era of spiritual activity is dawning upon the people of that land. May the repeated promises of ‘Abdu’l-Bahá regarding the ultimate religious revival of that spiritually conservative country, and the universal and whole-hearted response of its people to the Call of Yá-Bahá’u’l-Abhá be speedily fulfilled!</p>
        <p></p>
        <p>the pioneer of the Cause in Canada, will soon be with us in the Holy Land, and I trust that after her visit to the Three Holy Shrines, she may be enabled to return, invigorated and refreshed, ready to continue, in collaboration with you all, the great mission which the Master has destined her to fulfill in this world. May I assure you again of my constant prayers for your success, and of my desire to hear from you all, individually and collectively, regarding the progress of your labours, and the plans you contemplate for the further advancement of the Movement in those regions.</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of [13] December 1923">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 1 February 1924">
        <p>to our dear Guardian, Shoghi Effendi, has been received. He was deeply impressed with the spirit of your devotion and attachment to the Holy Cause of God and lofty aspirations to serve humanity which is the fundamental aim of the Bahá’í Movement.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>with us. We are impressed deeply with his love, devotion and sincerity or in other words, with his Bahá’í spirit. We are sure that when he returns to Canada, through the inspiration he has received from his personal touch with our beloved Guardian and from the Holy Shrine of our Master, he will be able to reach the hearts of the people with a greater power than ever before.</p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 4 February 1924">
        <p>has served to remind me of my Canadian friends, who are destined and chosen by Bahá’u’lláh to prepare the way for the ultimate triumph of His Cause in that great and vast Dominion.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>That pioneer worker of the Cause, so precious an asset to the Movement in Canada, will soon be in your midst, refreshed and restored. I am waiting with intense expectation to see your individual activities and talents all merged into one motive force, sustained by your combined efforts, directed by a unified purpose, and inspired by one common aim. Then will the showers of His grace rain upon you, and the unfailing promises of ‘Abdu’l-Bahá be speedily and effectively fulfilled.</p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 16 October 1924">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of January 1926">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>and Mrs. Schopflocher with us. They tell us about your Assemblies in Canada and the wonderful success you have had in teaching and interesting the people. I really hope your group will increase from day to day and achieve great things in the path of God.</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 9 August 1926">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 2 December 1926">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 10 December 1926">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 10 March 1927">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 12 April 1927">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 13 April 1927">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 4 May 1927">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 25 August 1927">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 27 October 1927">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 7 March 1928">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 26 April 1928">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 6 May 1928">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 10 October 1928">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 25 October 1928">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 20 March 1929">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 4 June 1929">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 20 September 1929">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 5 January 1930">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 3 January 1932">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 18 January 1932">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 10 February 1932">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 1 April 1932">
        <p>will find in it many interesting facts to incorporate in his review of the progress of the Faith during the last two years.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 26 April 1932">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 20 August 1932">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 10 September 1932">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 21 October 1932">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 1 June 1933">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 8 March 1934">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 30 April 1934">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 3 December 1934">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 18 June 1935">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of [no date indicated]">
        <p></p>
        <p>visit to your centre will serve to impart to your heart a fresh encouragement, as well as a more powerful incentive to carry on your work for the Cause.</p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 17 March 1936">
        <p>AND YOUR DEAR SELF.</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 11 December 1936">
        <p></p>
        <p>and Gerrard Sluter, the only active believers besides you in Toronto. It is his fervent hope that your united endeavours will greatly stimulate the promotion of the teaching work in that centre. May Bahá’u’lláh send down upon you His confirmations, and assist you in the attainment of this supreme objective.</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 12 April 1937">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Canada’s Involvement in the First Teaching Plans 1937–1948">
        <p>and he wishes me to hasten to assure your community of his heartfelt appreciation of the sentiments of devoted love and loyalty you have expressed, all of which he dearly prizes indeed.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 11 August 1937">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 11 February 1938">
        <p></p>
        <p>a group of thirteen believers has been formed in Moncton, and he cherishes the hope that this truly splendid start that has been made will be followed up by careful and well-planned teaching activity. He would urge you and each one of your fellow-believers to gird the loins of endeavour in this path, and to exert yourselves day and night until this supreme task is accomplished.</p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 27 February 1938">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 17 March 1938">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 22 April 1938">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 3 May 1938">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>is obtaining during her teaching travels to various parts of the States, and particularly in California. Her great zeal, and the talents she is displaying in the teaching field are indeed assets to the teaching force in America, which the friends cannot but value and fully utilize.</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 17 July 1938">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 26 January 1939">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 22 April 1939">
        <p></p>
        <p>for whom you had asked his special prayers in your last letter, have joined the Toronto Bahá’í Community, and are progressing so well spiritually. He will continue to remember them in his prayers that they may keep on deepening in their devotion and love for the Cause, and that also they may receive ever-widening opportunities of promoting its truth, and of extending its foundations in their centre.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 28 April 1939">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 18 July 1939">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 3 August 1939">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 25 August 1939">
        <p>whom you have already confirmed, this goal should not prove impossible of attainment, and it is to be hoped that as soon as the holiday season is over you will jointly endeavour to start a regular study group which will form the nucleus of the future Bahá’í Assembly of Calgary.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 2 March 1940">
        <p>ADVISE INTERMENT BUENOS AIRES. HER TOMB DESIGNED BY YOURSELF ERECTED BY ME SPOT SHE FOUGHT FELL GLORIOUSLY WILL BECOME HISTORIC CENTRE PIONEER BAHÁ’Í ACTIVITY. MOST WELCOME ARRANGE AFFAIRS RESIDE HAIFA BE ASSURED DEEPEST LOVING SYMPATHY.</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 22 April 1940">
        <p>NOBLE EXAMPLE LOVE.</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 28 June 1941">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 10 July 1941">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 24 September 1941">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 19 October 1941">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 23 March 1942">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 12 April 1942">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 15 April 1942">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 8 May 1942">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 15 June 1942">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 29 July 1942">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 14 October 1942">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>and his wife was most welcome. He is, indeed, a very devoted Bahá’í, as is Ernest Harrison also, and the Guardian is happy to know you have been able to study the teachings with such fine believers as these.</p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 15 November 1942">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 5 May 1943">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 26 May 1943">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 22 June 1943">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 19 December 1943">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 30 March 1944">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 6 July 1944">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 16 October 1944">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 13 November 1944">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 6 April 1945">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 16 May 1945">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 29 October 1945">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 22 March 1946">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 24 March 1946">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>your teaching trips, and your local Bahá’í work—are very deeply appreciated by him, and he rejoices to see you and your dear wife toiling so faithfully in the service of our beloved Cause. In this connection he wishes to thank you for the copies of your book which you sent him and which he placed in various Bahá’í libraries here.</p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 12 June 1946">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 24 July 1946">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 28 December 1946">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 19 February 1947">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>has, likewise, been a very useful addition to the teaching literature of the Faith in English, and you must rejoice to see the way God is blessing your labours for His Cause.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 15 March 1947">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 7 April 1947">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 14 April 1947">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 14 April 1947">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 20 April 1947">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 6 May 1947">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 4 July 1947">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 23 August 1947">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 27 September 1947">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 14 October 1947">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 14 October 1947">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 10 December 1947">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 14 December 1947">
        <p>PRAYING ARDENTLY PROGRESS SOUL ABHÁ KINGDOM RECORD HER MERITORIOUS SERVICES WILL NEVER BE FORGOTTEN.</p>
    </section>
    <section title="The Birth of the Independent Canadian Bahá’í Community and the Five Year Plan 1948–1953">
        <p>WHOSE LIFE DEATH FORGED UNBREAKABLE LINKS BINDING BODY CANADIAN BELIEVERS SISTER COMMUNITIES UNITED STATES LATIN AMERICA. MOVED APPEAL ASSEMBLED DELEGATES ARISE CONJUNCTION FIRST CANADIAN NATIONAL ASSEMBLY TOKEN GRATITUDE MANIFOLD BLESSINGS DIVINE PROVIDENCE INITIATE HOUR BIRTH THEIR NATIONAL ACTIVITIES FIVE YEAR PLAN DESIGNED ASSOCIATE THEM FORMALLY SYSTEMATICALLY INDEPENDENTLY SISTER COMMUNITY UNITED STATES COMMON TASK PROSECUTION WORLD ENCOMPASSING MISSION. FULFILMENT THIS COLLECTIVE TASK CONFRONTING RAPIDLY MATURING COMMUNITY NECESSITATES INCORPORATION CANADIAN NATIONAL ASSEMBLY ESTABLISHMENT NATIONAL BAHÁ’Í ENDOWMENTS DOUBLING NUMBER LOCAL ASSEMBLIES THROUGHOUT DOMINION RAISING TO ONE HUNDRED TOTAL NUMBER LOCALITIES WHERE BAHÁ’ÍS RESIDE THROUGHOUT PROVINCES CONSTITUTION GROUP NEWFOUNDLAND FORMATION NUCLEUS FAITH TERRITORY GREENLAND SINGLED OUT SPECIAL MENTION AUTHOR DIVINE PLAN PARTICIPATION ESKIMOS RED INDIANS MEMBERSHIP SHARE ADMINISTRATIVE PRIVILEGES LOCAL INSTITUTIONS FAITH CANADA. FONDLY HOPE ARDENTLY PRAY CELEBRATION FIRST CENTENARY BIRTH BAHÁ’U’LLÁH’S PROPHETIC MISSION WILL WITNESS TRIUMPHANT CONSUMMATION FIRST HISTORIC PLAN LAUNCHED CANADIAN BAHÁ’Í COMMUNITY IN LAND WHOSE FUTURE GREATNESS GLORY BOTH MATERIALLY SPIRITUALLY CENTRE BAHÁ’U’LLÁH’S COVENANT TWICE EMPHATICALLY PROCLAIMED HIS IMMORTAL TABLETS.</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 28 April 1948">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 16 September 1948">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 15 October 1948">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 4 November 1948">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 23 November 1948">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 12 January 1949">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 16 March 1949">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 1 April 1949">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 21 April 1949">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 2 May 1949">
        <p>UNIQUE ANNALS FAITH EAST WEST. GLORIOUS EVENTS FORESHADOWED BY ‘ABDU’L-BAHÁ TABLETS DIVINE PLAN LONG LAST UNFOLDING. NATIONAL ELECTED REPRESENTATIVES NEWLY FLEDGED HIGHLY PROMISING RICHLY BLESSED COMMUNITY DESERVE HEARTIEST CONGRATULATIONS. APPEAL ITS MEMBERS ARISE TOKEN GRATITUDE OUTPOURING DIVINE GRACE BESTOWED INITIAL STAGE ITS INDEPENDENT DEVELOPMENT VIGOROUSLY PROSECUTE PLAN ATTAIN ALL OBJECTIVES SET IMPERISHABLE EXAMPLE SISTER COMMUNITIES BAHÁ’Í WORLD. ARDENTLY PRAYING STILL GREATER VICTORIES.</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 9 May 1949">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 19 June 1949">
        <p></p>
        <p>relating to the official status of your Assembly was a cause for great rejoicing, as this is the first time in Bahá’í history that any government has taken such action in relation to our Faith’s status. He would like, if possible, to receive duplicates of the official Gazette and all publicity given this matter, as the copies you sent were placed in the Mansion at Bahji, but he wishes to have these documents at hand in his personal files as well.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 5 July 1949">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 5 August 1949">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 5 August 1949">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 22 August 1949">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 23 August 1949">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 4 September 1949">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 17 September 1949">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 24 September 1949">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 30 September 1949">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 20 October 1949">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 26 October 1949">
        <p>—such devoted and fine believers—gave you assistance when you needed it.</p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 13 November 1949">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 24 November 1949">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 18 December 1949">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 19 March 1950">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 4 April 1950">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 9 April 1950">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 1 May 1950">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 23 June 1950">
        <p></p>
        <p>has been dangerously and desperately ill. The anxiety this caused us all, and the constant coming and going of doctors, nurses, and two periods in hospital, has necessitated putting aside all correspondence for months. Now, however, thank God, Mr. Maxwell is slowly improving, and the threads of normal existence can be taken up again by us all.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>in Newfoundland; this has accomplished one of the specific desires of the beloved Master, and will redound to the glory of the Canadian Bahá’ís.</p>
        <p>into Greenland. This is fraught with many difficulties, but he urges your Assembly to persevere and exert its utmost to remove every obstacle. He will specially pray that a way may open for her to enter that country.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p>He is very anxious that no new rules and regulations should be introduced. As far as possible each National Spiritual Assembly should decide secondary matters for itself, and not try to lay down a rule general in application.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p>who returned from the United States in order to pioneer amongst his own people, in teaching the Canadian Indians, is one of the most important fields of activity under your jurisdiction. The Guardian hopes that ere long many of these original Canadians will take an active part in Bahá’í affairs and arise to redeem their brethren from the obscurity and despondency into which they have fallen.</p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 17 July 1950">
        <p></p>
        <p>it is wonderful news you give him that Mr. Fuller will be in Greenland for nine months! God seems to have arranged for one believer to be on the spot until your Assembly can get a real pioneer there.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 3 September 1950">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 11 September 1950">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 30 September 1950">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 30 September 1950">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 4 October 1950">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>and Mr. Fuller will be there temporarily, and they should investigate all possibilities and report to your Assembly.</p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 30 October 1950">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 2 November 1950">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of January 1951">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 1 March 1951">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>his deep appreciation of the unique service she is rendering the Cause, and of the exemplary spirit which is animating her. He hopes other believers will follow in her footsteps, and arise to do work in this very important field of Bahá’í activity.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p>had gone north and had been able to contact the Arctic Eskimos. He hopes that the way will open for this devoted believer to establish a more permanent contact in that area in some field of government work.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 29 April 1951">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 4 May 1951">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 27 July 1951">
        <p></p>
        <p>and was overjoyed to see such a fine, conscientious soul was going to Greenland as a pioneer. Let us hope he will get results, as no doubt his task will require great tact.</p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 30 October 1951">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>for the Arctic made the Guardian very happy; this, as well as the sailing of Mr. Bischoff for Greenland, marks the opening stage of the campaign to carry the Faith to the Eskimos, a plan set forth by ‘Abdu’l-Bahá and very dear to His heart.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 31 October 1951">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 25 November 1951">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 25 December 1951">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 3 March 1952">
        <p>and he has instructed me to answer you on his behalf.</p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 14 April 1952">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 27 April 1952">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 28 April 1952">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 14 May 1952">
        <p>BE MAINTAINED OR NOT LEFT ASSEMBLY’S DISCRETION. CONSIDER MATTER OBJECTIVELY. ARRANGING SEND TWO THOUSAND POUNDS MY CONTRIBUTION FUTURE HAZÍRÁ URGE ENERGETIC EFFORTS</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 20 May 1952">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 20 May 1952">
        <p></p>
        <p>and feels sure that they will come as a Body to a wise decision....</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 8 June 1952">
        <p>November 28, 1951, February 15, March 17 and April 19, 1952, signed by Laura R. Davis and May 15, 1952 signed by Ross Woodman, with their various enclosures, have been received, and the beloved Guardian has requested me to answer you on his behalf.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>The word that you marked in red is “Ark”.</p>
        <p>when he was here, upon the advisability of maintaining the Laurentian School, in an objective spirit. The Guardian can only outline to you the principle, which is that Bahá’í funds should not be invested in building up a place that has dear associations for a number of the friends, but is not going to really serve a large group of the believers. We are all familiar with the tremendous sums that have gone into the upkeep of Green Acre over the years, without so far bringing returns commensurate with the investment of our limited Bahá’í monies. However Green Acre, through its close association with the Master, undoubtedly has historic importance, and for this reason cannot be abandoned.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>His association, not only with Canada and the inception of the Faith there, but with the World Centre and the Shrine of the Báb, naturally endears him to all the friends, and his grave should be a national memorial. When the time comes to erect the tomb-stone, the question of receiving contributions from your Body can be considered.</p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 15 June 1952">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 18 June 1952">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 28 July 1952">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 2 August 1952">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 5 August 1952">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 22 August 1952">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 24 August 1952">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>Mr. Maxwell rendered outstanding and distinguished service to the Cause and to the Guardian during a very difficult period of its development here. Rúhíyyih ánum likewise is deeply appreciative of this remembrance of Mr. Maxwell.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 19 September 1952">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 19 September 1952">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 29 November 1952">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 8 February 1953">
        <p>and he has asked me to acknowledge it on his behalf. The receipt for the contribution was taken to you by Mr. Rakovsky.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 5 April 1953">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Canada’s Part in the Ten Year World Spiritual Crusade 1953–1957">
        <p>TWO ASIA MARQUESAS ISLANDS SAMOA ISLANDS SECOND CONSOLIDATION FAITH ICELAND GREENLAND MACKENZIE NEWFOUNDLAND THIRD PURCHASE LAND TORONTO ANTICIPATION CONSTRUCTION FIRST MARIQU’L-AKÁR CANADA FOURTH ESTABLISHMENT NATIONAL BAHÁ’Í ENDOWMENTS FIFTH DOUBLING NUMBER LOCAL SPIRITUAL ASSEMBLIES SIXTH RAISING NUMBER INCORPORATED SPIRITUAL ASSEMBLIES NINETEEN SEVENTH FORMATION ISRAEL BRANCH CANADIAN NATIONAL SPIRITUAL ASSEMBLY EIGHTH ESTABLISHMENT AMERICAN ASIAN TEACHING COMMITTEES ENTRUSTED TASK STIMULATE COORDINATE TEACHING ACTIVITIES INITIATED PLAN. APPEAL MEMBERS ENTIRE COMMUNITY WORTHY ALLIES CHIEF EXECUTORS DIVINE PLAN DEDICATE THEMSELVES IMMEDIATE REQUIREMENTS STEADILY UNFOLDING MISSION DISCHARGE NOBLY SACRED STRENUOUS TASKS AHEAD CONTRIBUTE MEMORABLE SHARE PROSECUTION DECADE LONG WORLD SPIRITUAL CRUSADE PAY BEFITTING TRIBUTE THROUGH FUTURE ACCOMPLISHMENTS MEMORY FOUNDER FAITH OCCASION MOST GREAT JUBILEE COMMEMORATING CENTENARY DECLARATION HIS MISSION CITY BADÁD.</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 22 April 1953">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 1 May 1953">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 9 [May] 1953">
        <p>MONTREAL ADVISE ALL FRIENDS GATHER GRAVE HAND CAUSE SUTHERLAND MAXWELL PAY TRIBUTE HIS IMMORTAL SERVICES WORLD CENTRE FAITH. INSTRUCTING MILLY PLACE BLOSSOMS SHRINE AND FRESH FLOWERS MY BEHALF. APPRECIATE PHOTOGRAPH FRIENDS ASSEMBLED GRAVE</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 23 May 1953">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 8 June 1953">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 20 June 1953">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>he feels, was an important milestone in the history of the Faith in Canada, and he hopes that it will be put to good use, during the coming years, by your Assembly. To this institution you will soon be adding the Maxwell Home in Montreal, which should be viewed in the nature of a national Shrine, because of its association with the beloved Master, during His visit to Montreal. He sees no objection to having one room in the house being used as a little museum associated with Mr. and Mrs. Maxwell.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>and, gradually, where the Cause is strong enough, in other Provinces.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 3 July 1953">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 15 July 1953">
        <p>FIRST NEGRO CANADIAN BAHÁ’Í.</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 26 July 1953">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 30 July 1953">
        <p>NUMEROUS MAGNIFICENT SERVICES EXTENDING OVER THIRTY YEARS ADMINISTRATIVE TEACHING SPHERES UNITED STATES CANADA INSTITUTIONS BAHÁ’Í WORLD CENTRE GREATLY ENRICHED ANNALS FORMATIVE AGE FAITH. ABUNDANT REWARD ASSURED ABHA KINGDOM. ADVISING AMERICAN NATIONAL ASSEMBLY HOLD BEFITTING MEMORIAL GATHERING TEMPLE HE GENEROUSLY HELPED RAISE. ADVISE HOLD MEMORIAL GATHERING MAXWELL HOME COMMEMORATE HIS EMINENT PART RISE ADMINISTRATIVE ORDER FAITH CANADA. URGE ENSURE BURIAL CLOSE NEIGHBOURHOOD RESTING PLACE DISTINGUISHED HAND CAUSE SUTHERLAND MAXWELL.</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 14 August 1953">
        <p></p>
        <p>and of the warm love he carried to you from the Guardian, and of the happiness and inspiration he brought you in his own loving spirit.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 20 August 1953">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 18 September 1953">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 28 December 1953">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 2 January 1954">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 7 February 1954">
        <p></p>
        <p>is a great loss to the work of the Faith, particularly in the teaching field, where she rendered such tireless and invaluable services, and where the need for such dedicated Bahá’ís is at the present time so great. However, we can be sure that her pure spirit can reinforce the work of the believers on this plane, and that she is now receiving her reward.</p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 8 February 1954">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 19 March 1954">
        <p>TOO FAR TOO EXPENSIVE</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 22 March 1954">
        <p>SETTLE COMORO BY THEN LOVING GREETINGS.</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 27 March 1954">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 29 March 1954">
        <p></p>
        <p>succeeds in going on a hunting trip there (providing his recent flight there has not shown him some other way of ingress to the land, or one of the other friends), he will find some means of contact and a possible opening.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 12 April 1954">
        <p>HAS CONTACTS ADVISE.</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 12 April 1954">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 18 April 1954">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 2 May 1954">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 4 May 1954">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 5 May 1954">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>have shown has moved him very deeply, and he hopes it will stir the Canadian Community, and impress upon them the advisability of answering the pioneer call now, while the field is open, and the opportunities and the rewards so glorious.</p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 6 May 1954">
        <p></p>
        <p>Of course, being in the military service, this may be impossible. On the other hand, perhaps you can give the exact location of Bruce Matthew, who is in Goose Bay.</p>
        <p>might be able to achieve success in connection with the location of someone in Anticosti. He realizes that this is a very difficult assignment, but feels that the hand of Bahá’u’lláh will assist those who arise to carry on this work, and that the doors will open, somehow or other. He hopes your committee and the National Assembly will realize the great importance of someone being settled in Anticosti, and will continue to press the matter.</p>
        <p>to leave the Queen Charlotte Islands in order to settle in some more distant area, it appears that Miss MacArthur is the only Bahá’í in the Queen Charlotte Islands and, inasmuch as this is one of the virgin areas of the Crusade, it would seem inadvisable for her to leave unless of course there are other pioneers who could enter it, or unless she has confirmed two or three of the people living permanently in that island.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>does leave Greenland this summer, that your committee will undertake to have a new pioneer there before he leaves. The teaching work in that important country must go forward, and the Guardian is hopeful that nothing whatsoever will prevent this being done.</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 14 May 1954">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>death, Rosemary and Emeric Sala’s departure and that of John Robarts and his family.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 21 May 1954">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 23 May 1954">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 4 June 1954">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 5 June 1954">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 15 June 1954">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>is going to be much felt. He was so intensely loyal, so vigilant in watching over the interests of the Faith, so steadfast and tenacious in serving it, that he will be much missed in the national work. For over thirty years, he promoted, not only the interests of the Faith, but those of the Canadian Bahá’í Community, and rendered on a national and an international scale, through contributions and many teaching trips, valuable services to the Cause of God.</p>
        <p>Montreal has indeed been blessed in more ways than one; and, as the Mother Community of Canada, should become increasingly active and united, and live up to the high expectations the Master cherished for her future, and prove herself worthy of the many blessings she has already received....</p>
        <p>, of your National Body for pioneer fields abroad. It should be a source of great pride that one-third of the membership of your Body set sail for such distant goals, and will render services during the Ten Year Crusade, of such a nature, he feels sure, as to bestow honour upon the entire Canadian Community.</p>
        <p>made to get a pioneer into it before last Ridván. No doubt eventually your efforts will be crowned with success; but you will have to be very tactful and careful in order not to arouse a permanently resistant attitude on the part of the Company that owns the Island.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 30 June 1954">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 5 September 1954">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 19 September 1954">
        <p>PRAYING SUCCESS</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 22 October 1954">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 27 October 1954">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 1 November 1954">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 24 November 1954">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 4 December 1954">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 4 December 1954">
        <p>of Verdun, Quebec, is making arrangements to go to Anticosti Island as the guest of a family living there.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 22 February 1955">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 23 February 1955">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 3 March 1955">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 11 March 1955">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 20 March 1955">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 20 March 1955">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 5 April 1955">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 23 April 1955">
        <p></p>
        <p>and discuss with him the possibility of ... getting a job in Bechuanaland, a difficult territory, and where there are only the Robarts pioneering at present.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 26 April 1955">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 1 May 1955">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 3 May 1955">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 24 May 1955">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 16 July 1955">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>in Montreal is really a national endowment he feels in conformity to the policy being pursued in other countries Canada should acquire one also at this time. This may be a small piece of land purchased for Two Thousand Dollars or even less, or for that matter, given to the National Assembly as a gift. The important point is that Canada should have its own National Endowment, as distinguished from the school property.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p>this your Body is free to use for the purposes of the Faith, at its discretion.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 3 September 1955">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 14 September 1955">
        <p></p>
        <p>that their return to Franklin was essential, and that his fervent prayers would accompany them.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 7 October 1955">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 19 October 1955">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 20 October 1955">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 21 October 1955">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 10 November 1955">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 14 December 1955">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 15 December 1955">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 13 January 1956">
        <p></p>
        <p>and he would like the National Assembly, with the greatest of care, to see that somehow or other in the foundation of the monument this piece of plaster is carefully inserted ; if necessary, the head-stone can be removed, and it can be put under it, and the head-stone rebuilt in such a way as not to damage the head-stone.</p>
        <p>On the other hand, Anticosti should be maintained as an objective; and every effort be made to get a Bahá’í in there.</p>
        <p>of your Assembly is visiting here, and, although unfortunately he has been laid up with a cold, it has been a great pleasure to have a Canadian Assembly member here.</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 30 January 1956">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 2 February 1956">
        <p>who is here at present.</p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 24 February 1956">
        <p>GRAVE ALSO STAR.</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 10 March 1956">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 20 March 1956">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 23 March 1956">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 28 April 1956">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 3 May 1956">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 6 May 1956">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 10 June 1956">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 26 June 1956">
        <p></p>
        <p>was immensely welcome, and enabled the Guardian to take off his list one of the few remaining virgin territories (aside from those under Soviet domination) on the list of countries to be opened to the Faith under the Ten Year Plan.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p>but never the blessing of resident local Bahá’ís. It deserves particular attention at this time.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>grave built. This is a task which is indeed a precious trust for your Assembly. When the friends realize that her grave will become in the future a place of visitation, they will appreciate the bounty bestowed upon the Canadian Community through being able to claim one of the most distinguished of all pioneers as a member of their Community.</p>
        <p>a member of your Assembly, as his guest here in the Holy Land, and he feels sure that this contact has forged yet another link between the Canadian Bahá’ís and the World Centre.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 1 July 1956">
        <p>in which he has acknowledged the gift made in behalf of his wife, for the work in Africa.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 1 July 1956">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 30 July 1956">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 25 August 1956">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 16 September 1956">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 10 October 1956">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 20 October 1956">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 3 December 1956">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 14 December 1956">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 20 December 1956">
        <p></p>
        <p>is continuing her valuable pioneer service there, to which he attaches great importance.</p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 22 December 1956">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>of your Assembly visiting Haifa, and hopes that Miss Harvey will carry back to you a fresh impetus from the Holy Land, which will assist the Canadian Assembly members in carrying on their many heavy burdens in the service of the Faith.</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 27 December 1956">
        <p></p>
        <p>concerning the subject, and she can and will amplify this communication.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 27 December 1956">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 15 January 1957">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 26 January 1957">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 2 February 1957">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 7 February 1957">
        <p></p>
        <p>conveyed to them. It makes a great difference to make the personal contact of a returning pilgrim, and the Guardian feels sure that many of the friends would arise and do pioneer work if they grasped the privilege and the importance of it. The contact with a visitor from Haifa is naturally a vivid experience, and he feels sure will be a great stimulation to not only the Ottawa friends but others.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 30 March 1957">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 30 April 1957">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 17 May 1957">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 21 May 1957">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 4 June 1957">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 7 July 1957">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 18 July 1957">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>and upholding his claims actively, then they would come into an entirely different category. If this is the case, you should inform the Guardian, but otherwise the friends should be advised to just leave these people alone, for their influence can be nothing but negative and destructive, and the less they breathe the breath, so to speak, of those who have turned their back on the light of this Faith, the better.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>the lone Canadian pioneer, is demonstrating the Bahá’í spirit in such an exemplary manner. It is hard for the friends to appreciate, when they are isolated in one of these goal territories, and see that they are making no progress in teaching others, are living in inhospitable climes for the most part, and are lonesome for Bahá’í companionship and activity, that they represent a force for good, that they are like a light-house of Bahá’u’lláh shining at a strategic point and casting its beam out into the darkness. This is why he so consistently urges these pioneers not to abandon their posts. Apropos of this, he hopes that it will again be possible in the near future to get someone into Anticosti. It is a great pity that the friend who went there could not remain.</p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 2 September 1957">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 9 September 1957">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 18 September 1957">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 18 September 1957">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 22 September 1957">
        <p>REMAIN MIQUELON UNTIL REPLACEMENT ARRIVES HE SENDS HER LOVING APPRECIATION.</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 26 September 1957">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 3 October 1957">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>He is truly one who kindles a new flame of love and longing to serve the Cause in the hearts of the believers wherever he goes.</p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 19 October 1957">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p>yourself are to be congratulated on the very wonderful work you have been doing with the Indians on the Tyendinaga Reserve. The Guardian greatly appreciates this service, and wishes you to know that he values it very highly. He hopes nothing will interfere with your carrying it forward to the fine conclusion which you hope will be the establishment of an Assembly on this reserve. It would be a distinct victory for the Faith if that is accomplished.</p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 7 November 1957">
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Letter of 5 November 1957">
        <p></p>
    </section>
    <section title="Appendix: Knights of Bahá’u’lláh">
        <p>that those believers who arose to pioneer to goals outlined in the Ten Year Crusade, would be designated “Knights of Bahá’u’lláh”, and would have their names inscribed on a “Roll of Honour”. This Roll was placed at the entrance door of the Shrine of Bahá’u’lláh in 1992, as instructed by the Guardian and noted in the 8 June 1953 letter in this book. Several of these Knights were Canadian, and others fulfilled Canadian goals.</p>
        <p></p>
        <p></p>
    </section>
</book>
